

Home: 813-210-5528 justinvalentine88@gmail.com Tampa - St. Pete, FL Available to relocate

Profile

Junior Developer specializing in Back end development, Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Strong background in project management and customer relations while showing the desire to learn more.

Skills

Ruby on Rails, Back end Web Development, SQL, MVC, HTML, CSS, API consuming & building, Agile Web Development, Responsive Design, Basic Ruby, Console Applications, ActiveRecord, CRUD, Javascript basics, ¡Query basics, and Ajax

Experience

JUNIOR DEVELOPER, THE IRON YARD, TAMPA, FL — 2017-PRESENT

While at The Iron Yard I designed and created web apps that served multiple purposes that ranged from a news aggregator, Real Estate listing site, auction site and a local social social communication site.

DISTRIBUTION SPECIALIST, BROWN DISTRIBUTING COMPANY, TAMPA, FL - 2015-2017

Local craft beer distribution for the Tampa bay area, was in charge of ensuring safe delivery of product to customers and offering advice on which new products they should receive.

STORE MANAGER, ALDO GROUP, NEW YORK, NY - 2011-2015

As Store Manager for Aldo my job entailed the hiring, training and evaluation of employees, customer service, supervision over sales and quota completions and tracking inventory.

ASSISTANT MANAGER, PUBLIX, TAMPA, FL - 2008-2011

The main focus of an Assistant Manager is customer service so the main area of the job was to do anything that will ensure customers had an engaging friendly experience. Other requirements included merchandise tracking, creating work schedule, and associate evaluations.

Education

The Iron Yard, Tampa, FL – Back end Engineering, 2017

Cooper Union, New York, NY – Architecture and Design, 2007-2008

Penn Foster High School, Scranton, PA – High School Diploma, 2007

Projects

WANDERER - HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JUSIXO/WANDERER - JUNE 2017

Wanderer is a social marketing app for outdoor events and festivals. Connecting people to a drones camera feed they can view the event and get photos from a new angle.

BIDTASTIC - HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JUSIXO/BIDTASTIC-MINUS-ONE - MAY 2017

Bidtastic is a charitable auction app that I was project lead on. The app was built mobile first and has the ability to host multiple auctions at a time. People can bid through the app and stay up to date with everything happening when the events timer ended the winners would automatically be informed.

HOUSEHUNTER - HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JUSIXO/HOUSEHUNTER - APRIL 2017

HouseHunter is an app that I created that was meant to show off skills I learned like using multiple databases, uploading images to a database, using authorization for signing in, javascript for real time search results, and action mailers.

FINDYRPET - HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JUSIXO/FINDYRPET - DUE AUGUST 2017

Find your pet is an app I am designing to help people locate any lost pets they see around their neighborhood. The app will use location with maps and a geotagging system along with photos and descriptions of the pets to create a engaging service to help people find their pets easily.